to find the area formula for a trapezoid
with bases of length B1 and B2 and a
height of length H we can perform the
following interesting process take one
of the side lengths and bict it cutting
it into two equal length pieces like
this now connect the midpoint to one of
the opposite Corners creating a small
triangle we can cut this triangle off
and rotate it around to create a larger
triangle with base of length B1 plus B2
and height of length H but then this
triangle has an area of/ 12 h * B1 + B2
as this triangle has the same area as
the original trapezoid we see that the
area formula for a trapezoid is 1/2 *
the height times the sum of the two
bases